Finding Aid for Grace Bible Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1939-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Grace Bible Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1939-2003
Grace Bible Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.).
8.5 linear feet
86781 Ba 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan independent non-denominational church; annual reports, constitution, doctrinal statements, minutes, bulletins, newsletters, and miscellaneous.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The executive committee of Grace Bible Church (donor no. 7398 ) first deposited its records with the library in 1986. Periodic additions have been received since then.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Grace Bible Church in Ann Arbor, Michigan is an independent non-denominational church. The church began as a Bible study meeting in a home. The founding date of the church was 1935.
The records include administrative files, topical files, women's groups, publication, and other materials. The administrative records series includes annual reports, minutes of the executive committee, and of congregational meetings.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Independent churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Administrative Records
  - Annual meeting, May 1, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Annual reports
    - 1954-2003, 3 expandable folders (Box 1)
      (some gaps)
  - Executive Committee minutes
    - 1948-1954 (Horace Pedigo) (Box 1)
    - 1950-1964 (Box 1)
    - 1950-1962 (Box 1)
    - 1963-1964 (Edwin Young file) (Box 1)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - 1962-1965 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 2)
      (includes some minutes of congregational meetings)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    - 1969-1975 (Box 2)
    - 1972-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1983 (Box 2)
    - 1984-1989 (Box 2)
  - Elders meetings, 1983-1989 (Box 2)
  - Monthly church meetings, 1939-1946 (Box 2)
  - Monthly church meetings, 1949-1965 (Box 2)
- Topical files
  - Bennett, William (GBC pastor) (Box 6)
  - Bethany Bible Church property (proposed use by Michigan Theological Seminary) (Box 6)
  - Camp Award Certificates, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Constitution, doctrinal statements, committee operating codes, etc. (Box 6)
  - Evangelism Committee, 1959-1963 (Box 6)
  - GBC News, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Hiawatha Beach Bible Church (Box 6)
  - Histories and other informational material (Box 6)
  - Membership lists (Box 6)
  - Missionary Committee, 1959-1964 (Box 6)
  - Photographs (Box 6)
  - Pictorial directories (Box 6)
  - Pulpit Committee (Theodore Knopf files), 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Saxe (Rev. Raymond): preliminary and background to his ouster (Box 6)
  - Saxe (Rev. Raymond): ouster from the church, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Sunday school teachers meetings, 1943 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Circles
  - Women of the Grace Bible Fellowship Minute book, 1942-1943 (Box 4)
  - Friendship Circle minutes and other materials, 1970-1983, 5 notebooks and 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Faithful Circle, 1960s-1970s, 1 binder (Box 4)
- Publications
  - Grace Notes (newsletter), 1969-1986, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Service bulletins, 1969-1978, 3 binders (Box 3)
  - Service bulletins, ca. 1949-ca. 1981 (unprocessed) (Box 5)
- Other materials
  - Audit reports (Box 7)
  - Financial receipts and bank statements (Box 7)
  - Hymnals (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous executive committee reports (probably duplicates) (Box 7)
  - Office topical files (Box 8)
  - 1970-1971 building program (Box 8)
  - Property warranty deeds (Box 8)
  - Files maintained by William Huizenga (Box 9)
  - Photographs taken by Arthur Asseltine (Box 9)
    (mainly during the building of the church on Maple Road, and its dedication)
  - Miscellaneous manuals and reports (Box 9)